hegartymaths.com 2019-07-07

# Keeping your information safe and secure

Keeping your information safe and secure
HegartyMaths are committed to protecting the privacy of our users wherever you or your school
provides us with your personal information.
We believe in being open and up front with how we use pupils and school staff personal information
and have developed our Privacy Promise, a quick and simple summary explaining how we manage,
share and look after your information. If you would like to know more about the we process your
personal data, please read our detailed Privacy Policy.
We have also created a Pupil Privacy Promise, to educate all of our pupils on the use of their personal
data (details), a copy of this can be found in the footer of the website.
For the most part at HegartyMaths, we process personal data about Pupils and School Staff on behalf of
and under the written instruction of a school. Should you have any questions about this use, please
contact your school directly.
We will decide how your personal data is used when you leave us an enquiry asking for information
about the HegartyMaths platform and to provide you a demonstration of the service. Should you have
any questions about this use, please contact our Data Protection Officer.
HegartyMaths Privacy Promise
We promise to collect, process, store and share your data safely and securely, by ensuring:
    ●   You’re always in control: Your privacy will be respected at all times and we will work with your
        school in upholding privacy.
    ●   We work transparently: We will be transparent about the data we receive and how we use that
        data.
    ●   We operate securely: We will protect the data that you entrust to us via appropriate security
        measures and controls. We’ll also ensure that other businesses we work with are just as careful
        with your data.
    ●   For your benefit: When we do process your data, we will use it to benefit all our pupils and
        school staff, to make your HegartyMaths experience better and to improve our products and
        services.

Who we are and how you can contact us
  HegartyMaths is a trading name of:
                        H&A Learning Limited
                        Devonshire House,
                        60 Goswell Road,
                        London,
                        United Kingdom,
                        EC1M 7AD
                        Registered Company Number:               09577195
                        ICO Registration Number:                 ZA321481
HegartyMaths have appointed a Data Protection Officer (DPO), who can be contacted in the following
ways should you have any questions about the way your data is handled:
        Email:          privacy@hegartymaths.com
        Mail:           Data Protection Officer
                        Suite 20-21 Winsor and Newton Building
                        Whitefriars Avenue
                        Harrow Wealdstone
                        London
                        HA3 5RN
Where we collect your personal information
We collect personal information about you in the following ways:
   1. Data you give to us:
            a. When you sign up for information about the HegartyMaths platform or to get a trial;
            b. When you talk to us on the phone;
            c. When you use our website;
            d. When you send communications to us via email, comment section on the platform or by
                post;
            e. When you give us feedback.
   2. Data from your school:
            a. When your school signs up for HegartyMaths;
            b. When your details are updated by your school.
   3. Data we collect about you
        We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we
        have grouped together as follows:

              a) Identity data (Pupils) – name, date of birth, gender, Unique Pupil Number and the
                  school you attend and your school leave date
              b) Identity data (School Staff) – name, job title and the school you work at;
              c) Contact data (School Staff) – email address or telephone number;
              d) User Agent data - browser type and version, operating system and device;
              e) Usage data – information about how and when you use HegartyMaths.
We also collect, use and share aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data for limited
purposes related to improving our platform. Aggregated data may be derived from your personal data
but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity.
For example, we may aggregate your usage data to calculate the percentage of users watching our
videos and the results they have received on the related tests.
We do not collect any special categories of personal data about you. This includes details about race or
ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union
membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any
information about criminal convictions and offences.
    How we use your personal information
We are only allowed to use personal information about you if we have a legal basis to do so, and we are
required to tell you what that legal basis is. We have set out in the table below: the personal
information which we collect from you, how we use it, and the legal ground which we rely on when we
use the personal information.
In some circumstances, we can use your personal information if it is in our legitimate interest to do so,
provided that we have told you what that legitimate interest is. A legitimate interest is when we have a
business or commercial reason to use your information which, when balanced against your rights, is
justifiable. If we are relying on our legitimate interests, we have set that out in the table below.
  What we use your           What personal                 Our legal grounds for    Our legitimate
  personal information       information we collect        processing               interests (if
  for                                                                               applicable)
  To maintain your          ●   Identity (Pupils)         ●   Performance of a      To provide an
  profile on our Platform   ●   Identity (School              contract              individual account
                                Staff)                    ●   Legitimate            for each user
                            ●   Contact                       interests             enrolled by schools
  To deliver maths          ●   Identity (Pupils)         ●   Performance of a      To provide
  education via our         ●   Identity (School              contract              education tools and
  platform                      Staff)                    ●   Legitimate            updates to those
                            ●   Contact                       interests             tools to all those
                                                                                    with active profiles
  To track pupil usage      ●   Identity (Pupils)         ●   Legitimate            To provide accurate
  and provide statistical   ●   Usage                         interests             information to
  information on                                                                    teachers about their
  progress                                                                          pupils

  To manage payments      ●   Identity (School       ●   Performance of a To recover any debts
  or collect and recover      Staff)                     contract         owed to us
  money owed to us        ●   Contact                ●   Legitimate
                                                         interests
  To manage our           ●   Identity (School       ●   Performance of a To keep our records
  relationship with you       Staff)                     contract         up to date
  and your school ,       ●   Contact                ●   Necessary to
  including notifying you ●   Transaction                comply with a
  about changes to our                                   legal obligation
  terms or Privacy                                   ●   Legitimate
  Notices                                                interests
  To administer and       ●   Transaction            ●   Legitimate       Running our
  protect our business,   ●   Technical                  interests        business, provision
  website and platform    ●   Usage                                       of administration
                                                                          and IT services,
                                                                          network security
  To use data analytics   ●   Technical              ●   Legitimate       To define users of
  and aggregated data     ●   Usage                      interests        our services, to keep
  to improve our          ●   Contact                                     our website and
  business, website and                                                   platform updated
  platform, user                                                          and relevant and to
  relationships and                                                       develop our business
  experiences
  To make contact with    ●   Identity (School       ●   Legitimate       To demonstrate our
  you regarding the           Staff)                     interests        services and sign up
  product and services    ●   Contact                                     new schools.
  offered by
  HegartyMaths
  To contact with you     ●   Identity (School       ●   Legitimate       To ensure there is no
  regarding your              Staff)                     interests        interruption to your
  contract renewal date ●     Contact                                     usage of the
                                                                          platform by
                                                                          renewing your
                                                                          contract in a timely
                                                                          manner.
Who we share your personal information with
If you are a member of staff at a school, we share your information with:
         ●    Wonde for integration with your schools MIS;

         ●    Hubspot to process enquiries about our platform and manage our relationships with our
              partner schools;
         ●    GrooveHQ to collect and organise queries submitted by school staff who use the
              HegartyMaths platform;
         ●    Xero to process our accounts;
         ●    Trello and Slack to manage our workflow and projects;
         ●    New Relic, Bugsnag and Cloud Flare to maintain, secure and improve our website and
              platform;
         ●    Mailchimp to keep you up to date with any changes or maintenance to our website or
              platform.
If you are a pupil, your information is only shared with Wonde in order to create and maintain your
HegartyMaths account.
If HegartyMaths is acquired by a third party, personal data held by us about our users, will be one of the
transferred assets.
We’ll never make your personal data available to anyone outside HegartyMaths for them to use for
marketing purposes without your prior consent.
Third party links
Our website may include links to third party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links
or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not
control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave
our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice or policy of every website you visit.
Transferring your personal information outside the EEA
In limited circumstances, we do transfer some personal data relating to school staff outside of the EEA.
When personal data is transferred outside of the EEA, we must tell you where it is going and what
safeguards are in place for that transmission. The organisations who receive personal data and the
safeguards in place for that data are as follows:
                            Service provided by    Geographical   Safeguard for transferring personal data
    Name of third party
                                 third party         location      outside of the European Economic Area
   Google LLC             Document creation            USA                  EU/US Privacy Shield
                          and storage
   Groove Networks,       Web application for          USA                  EU/US Privacy Shield
   LLC                    helpdesk support
   Hubspot, Inc           Sales CRM system             USA                  EU/US Privacy Shield

  The Rocket Science     Mass mailing platform          USA                     EU/US Privacy Shield
  Group LLC t/a
  Mailchimp
  Slack Technologies,    Internal                       USA                     EU/US Privacy Shield
  Inc                    communication tool
                         for HegartyMaths
                         employees
  Trello, Inc            Project management             USA                     EU/US Privacy Shield
                         tool
  Xero Ltd               Accounting software       New Zealand        New Zealand has an Adequacy Decision
                                                                     given by the European Commission; Xero
                                                                      enter into Standard Contractual Clauses
                                                                        where their processing takes place
                                                                              outside of New Zealand.
No data relating to pupils is transferred outside of the EEA.
Data security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being
accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit
access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a
business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are
subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and where relevant
will notify data controllers, you and any applicable regulator (including the ICO) of a breach where we
are legally required to do so.
How long do we keep your personal information
We will keep your personal information for as long as you are an active user on HegartyMaths.
After you stop being an active user, because you have stopped regularly using our services or left the
school which has enrolled you, we may keep your personal information for 24 months from the end of
that academic year for one of the following reasons:
          ●   To respond to any questions or complaints from you;
          ●   To maintain our records;
          ●   To provide the information should your HegartyMaths account be reactivated;
          ●   To comply with laws applicable to us.
After such time, we will securely delete your personal information.

If we receive a bounceback from any of the emails that we send to you on a number of occasions, we
may delete your personal information in relation to those emails at our discretion.
Marketing
We may use the personal information of a specific member of school staff to tell you about your
contract renewal date.
This is the only processing undertaken which would be considered as a direct marketing communication
under the Privacy and Electronic Regulations (2003).
Your rights
You have the following rights with regard to your personal data:
     ●   The right to be informed – this privacy notice explains to you how your personal data is
         processed by us.
     ●   The right of access – you can request that we provide you with a copy of all of the personal data
         that we hold about you.
     ●   The right to rectification – please let us know if any of the information we hold about you is
         incorrect so that we can correct it.
     ●   The right to erasure – you have the right to have your data ‘erased’ in the following situations:
              ○ where the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purpose for which it
                  was originally collected or processed;
              ○ when the personal data was unlawfully processed;
              ○ when the personal data has to be erased in order to comply with a legal obligation.
We will erase your records only where one of the above situations apply.
     ●   The right to restrict processing – you have the right to restrict processing in certain situations
         such as:
              ○ where you contest the accuracy of your personal data, we will restrict the processing
                  until you have verified the accuracy of your personal data;
              ○ when processing is unlawful, and you oppose erasure and request restriction instead;
              ○ where we no longer need the personal data, but you require the data to establish,
                  exercise or defend a legal claim.
     ●   The right to object - you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data in the
         following circumstances:
              ○ Where the processing is based on legitimate interests; and
              ○ Processing for purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics.
If you are a pupil, you will have to make these requests to your school.

Making a complaint
Please let us know if you are unhappy with how we have used your personal information by contacting
the Data Protection Officer.
You also have a right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office. You can find their contact
details at www.ico.org.uk. We would be grateful for the chance to deal with your concerns before you
approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.
